#### Ben Hilliard

Address: 23 Copas Dr

Klemzig SA 5087

Contact Phone: 0468 850 935

Email Address: <u>benhilliard23@hotmail.com</u>
GitHub: <u>https://github.com/BH-2312</u>

Portfolio Page: https://bh-2312.github.io/PortfolioPage/

# **Summary of Skills**

Full stack developer who is excited about a future in the industry. I have 10 years' experience in financial advice and believe that the skills learnt in this field can be transferred across to web development. I have proven myself to be trustworthy and personable, key attributes when building rapport with clients and colleagues. I thrive when working in a team environment and have a passion for mentoring and coaching.

## **Web Development**

I have a passion for web development and am excited to grow a career in this field. I am skilled at both front-end and back-end coding and have expertise in the following areas; HTML, CSS, Javascript, mobile-first web design, API's, node.js, MYSQL and MongoDB. As a recent student of the Adelaide University Coding BootCamp, I have been able to learn and practice working with these applications and have been able to create a portfolio of applications.

#### **Quality, Trusting Relationships**

Building quality, trusting relationships with key stakeholders has been key in my success throughout my career. My role at ANZ relied on me building these relationships to ensure that I received the required quality referrals. My experience coaching cricket and mentoring disabled job seekers has helped me to further understand the importance of building relationships and dealing with different personality types. During my web development studies, I have thoroughly enjoyed being involved in team projects and on each occasion was very proud of what we achieved in a short space of time.

## **Client Service and Presentation Skills**

As a financial adviser, I met with clients regularly to discuss their financial goals and put plans in place to achieve these goals. I was able to build a large base of ongoing clients and effectively sell the value of my advice. I understand that every client is different and have developed effective communication skills that allow me to tailor my presentation and delivery skills as required. I enjoy public speaking and during my web development studies, I was able to co-ordinate and deliver presentations of our projects.

#### Education

University of Adelaide Coding Boot Camp, 2020

Advanced Diploma of Financial Services (Financial Planning), 2015

Diploma of Financial Services (Financial Planning), 2010

Diploma of Financial Services (Finance/Mortgage Broking), 2012

University of Adelaide, Bachelor of Economics, 2006

## **Employment History**

#### Date

Date: Jun 2020 –

Company: Platinum Strategies Title: Client Relationship Assistant

Duties: Part time role whilst completing my Coding BootCamp studies. Performed advice

support duties such as product research, strategy research, contacting clients and

compliance.

Date: Jan 2014- May 2020

Company: ANZ Financial Planning Title: Senior Financial Planner

Duties: Providing high quality, compliant financial advice to my clients. The advice I provide in this role varied however there was a focus on risk protection and retirement planning. I built trusting relationships with referral partners which was essential in ensuring that I receive a steady stream of referrals. I consistently achieved my set targets and was able to grow from an associate to a senior planner. Through my employment at ANZ, I was fortunate to be involved in the PACE program, mentoring a disabled job seeker and the SA Future Leaders program, helping further develop my leadership skills.

Date: Sep 2009 – Dec 2013

Company: Gem Planning Pty Ltd (Accredited by AMPFP)

Title: Financial Planner

Duties: Meeting with clients, discussing their financial goals and implementing financial plans to achieve these goals. Within this role, I also completed my Diploma of Finance / Mortgage Broking, allowing me to become a qualified mortgage broker and provide lending solutions to clients that fit with their financial goals.

Date: Apr 2009 – Aug 2009

Company: Stafflex (Yorkshire, UK)

Title: Temporary Employee

Duties: A variety of temporary positions whilst in the UK on a working holiday.

Date: Oct 2006 – Mar 2009

Company: AAMI (Australian Associated Motor Insurers)

Title: Business Analyst

Duties: Analysing sales, claims and profitability data and making recommendations to management based on my results. The first point of contact in South Australia for any analysis of motor vehicle insurance data, such as, recommending price changes, profitability tracking and analysis of claims data. My successful business recommendations included targeting specific regions to improve new business sales and customer retention, altering the premium formula to maximise profitability and identifying vehicle types that required premium increases/decreases.

Date: 1999 - 2006

A variety of different roles whilst completing high school and university studies. These include customer service roles in retail sales and hospitality.

# **Interests**

I am the current 1st Grade Coach at the Adelaide University Cricket Club.